in recent years the vietnamese insurance
market
has made strong progress in terms of
both market size and
value the insurance business is
developing
safely and with stability in the context
of complicated pandemic diseases
capital mobilization for 2020 stock
market economy
increased by about 20 percent over the
previous year
changes in the number of insurance
enterprises over the past 10 years
show that the number of life insurance
and non-life insurance companies
has been quite stable reinsurance
enterprises remained
at two entities between 2011 and 2020
in vietnam there are two main
sub-sectors in the insurance industry
which are life insurance and non-life
insurance
in the context of vietnam joining free
trade agreements
most recently cptpp and evfta
the insurance supervisory authority is
continuing the process of perfecting
mechanisms
guidance and focus on innovation to help
the insurance market develop
transparently
securely and successfully according to
globally accepted standards
in 2020 the government continued to
issue new decrees and circulars
improving the legal framework of
insurance businesses making them more
suitable for opening up
and to deal with the impact of the kovic
pandemic by the end of 2020 the vietnam
market had 69
companies operating in the insurance
segment
at present out of 31 non-life insurance
companies
there are 16 foreign invested
enterprises and 17
out of 18 life insurance companies in
vietnam are foreign invested enterprises
total assets of non-life insurers were
estimated at
100 215 billion vietnamese don
while total primary insurance premium
was 55 094 billion
vietnamese dong in 2020 rising by 3.2
percent
over the same period in 2019
in terms of operations automobile
insurance
accounted for the largest proportion in
total revenue
followed by health insurance property
and casualty insurance
fire and explosion insurance and cargo
insurance
although the growth rate decreased
compared to 2019
the life insurance market still achieved
good results in 2020
market size tripled compared to 2015 in
terms of total premium revenue
total assets total investment and
owner's equity
investment linked accounts for the
largest proportion in life insurance
activity
followed by endowment term life and
others
activities in 2020
there were 18 insurance brokers in
vietnam
insurance brokerage activities performed
mainly in the field of non-life
insurance
accounting for 78.3 of the total
settlement fee
two players in vietnam's reinsurance
market are pvire
and vin are both firms saw significant
growth in premiums revenue
however future profits are expected to
remain the same
in recent years insurance has and
continues to be
a key point in the growth strategy of
many commercial banks
according to life insurance companies
statistics the new
insurance premium revenue accounted for
about 90
of the total market premium of which
bank assurance contributed
30 foreign insurance companies have
continuously developed
through the bank assurance banking
channel the many
exclusive contracts signed show that
foreign businesses are
constantly expanding their operations in
the vietnamese market
these were the highlights of vietnam's
insurance industry in 2020
by vietnam credit thank you for watching
if you enjoyed it make sure to check out
the vietnam credit channel for more
informative videos